SUCHINLIN

User Experience Designer

% | 646-784-5590⊠ | suchinUX@gmail.comwww.suchinlin.com

ABOUT ME

A bit about me and my "why" to designing:

I love helping people. Whether it's through projects or even something as simple as a passing greeting, I enjoy uplifting spirits and lightening loads. It's what brought me into nursing and now to user experience design.

Apart from design, I also am an avid runner and enjoy the discipline, expression, and community that comes with it.

SKILLS

Design Tools

Figma
Empathy
Sketch
Compassion
Invision
Creativity
Procreate
Leadership

UX Skills

- User Research
- Competitive Research
- Comparative Research
- Persona
- Sketching
- Storyboarding
- Prototyping
- Wireframing
- Interaction Design
- Usability Testing

EXPERIENCE

NFT PROJECT

Co-Founder and Designer

Sept 2021 to Present

- Hand-drew 230 total attributes for our 5-tier 10,000 piece collection
- Designed the UI, including interactions, for our custom marketplace
- Created website assets, promotional social media materials and content, as well as all instructional materials
- Managed and engaged with our 400+ member follower base

POLLTAB

UX/UI Designer

Feb 2021 to Aug 2021

- Conducted heuristic evaluation of client's website, desktop and mobile, and implemented 3 key UI design changes to improve users' flow - updates to CTA buttons, imagery, and color-scheme
- Built foundations for updated style guide in brand's redesign

PERSONAL PORTFOLIO DESIGN

UX/UI Designer

May 2020 to Present

- Collaborated with an engineer to launch 2 variations of my portfolio
- Developed and designed style guidelines (typography, color scheme, and components) and high fidelity prototypes on Figma
- Created personalized icons for portfolio use

MAKE AMERICA DINNER AGAIN

UX Design Consultant

April 2020

- Spearheaded team of 3 to better understand users' experiences and identify potential UX/UI friction points
- Conducted and synthesized research to guide design decisions 6 email interviews, 20 responses to custom-made survey, and 149 responses from client's existing survey
- Delineated users' experiences in a user journey map and created a low-mid fidelity prototype addressing identified friction points

MOUNT SINAI BETH ISRAEL, 32-bed Cardiac Tele / Stroke Unit

Registered Nurse, Unit Team Lead

Nov 2009 - July 2019

- Redesigned information boards and patient data collection forms
- Researched uptodate practices for policy and procedure committee
- Led team of 14 nurses and support staff through 12 hr day shifts

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Jan - Apr 2020

General Assembly

Visual Design Workshop

May 2020

New York University

UX Design Immersive

B.S. Nursing

Sept 2005 - May 2009

Udemy

Drawing and Painting with Procreate May 2021